Guide to the W. M. (William Moore) Gorman Papers, 1940s-1980s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
W. M. (William Moore) Gorman papers 1940s-1980s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Gorman, W. M. (William Moore), 1923-
42 linear feet Extent: 25,000 Items
Economist and professor of economics at Nuffield College, Oxford University, and London School of Economics. Gorman's principal fields of interest were general economic theory, econometrics, and international trade theory. This collection includes the professional correspondence, writings, unpublished notes, research reports, and other papers that document the academic career and research of the economist William M. Gorman. His writings include typescripts and handwritten manuscripts of published research. The correspondence segment chiefly holds letters of reference and correspondence received from colleagues. The collection also includes an index to Gorman's work.
RL.00466
Language: Material inEnglish
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The W. M. (William Moore) Gorman Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1998.
Biographical Note
Economist and professor of economics at Nuffield College, Oxford University, and London School of Economics. Gorman's principal fields of interest were general economic theory, econometrics, and international trade theory.
Collection Overview
This collection includes the professional correspondence, writings, unpublished notes, research reports, and other papers that document the academic career and research of the economist William M. Gorman. His writings include typescripts and handwritten manuscripts of published research. The correspondence segment chiefly holds letters of reference and correspondence received from colleagues. The collection also includes an index to Gorman's work.
Subject Headings
Gorman, W. M (William Moore), 1923-; London School of Economics and Political Science -- Faculty; Economists -- United States -- Correspondence; Economics -- History -- 20th century; Economics -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Great Britain -- History; Econometrics; International trade
Contents of Collection
- Accession (1998-0278), 1940s-1980s, (28 boxes)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 2 computer tapes (Box 1)
    - Separability and Aggregation: Collected Works of W.M. Gorman, Vol 1. (Box 1)
    - Index-W.M.G. papers in boxes-through early 1980s (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Unsorted (Box 2)
    - Polynominal Engel Curves, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Indirect Taxes, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Psuedo Separability, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Polynominal Engel Curves, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Generalised Additive Separability, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Variable Goods, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Ags. in Short and Long Run, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Doing Economics Economically, 1984, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Doing Economics Economically, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Doing Economics Economically, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Doing Economics Economically, undated (Box 4)
    - 610, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - 609, (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - Consumer Budgets and Price Indices, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Duality, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Duality and its Applications, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Empirical Demand Analysis (Box 5)
    - Reprints, 1967-1990 (Box 5)
    - Reprints, 1953-1964 (Box 5)
    - Undergraduate Dissertation, 1948 (Box 5)
    - 1977 (Box 5)
    - Doing Economics Economically, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Linear Affine Transformations, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Profit Functions, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Quasi-Separable Preferences, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Generalised Additive Separability (rough draft), 1971 (Box 5)
    - Demand For Water (Box 5)
    - Some Engel Curves, 1978-1982 (Box 6)
    - Vintage Capital, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Measuring Quantity in Fixed Factors, 1967 (Box 6)
    - The Structure of Utility Functions, 1967, ( 2 folders) (Box 6)
    - The Structure of Utility Functions (revised), 1967 (Box 6)
    - The Structure of Utility Functions, (rough draft), 1967, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Topics in the Theory of Aggregation, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Aggregates for Variable Goods, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Capital Aggregation in Vintage Models (Box 6)
    - Aggregates for Variable Goods (Box 6)
    - Concavity of Additive Utility Function, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Generalised Additive Separability, 1972, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Income Distribution, 1978 (Box 7)
    - More Measures for Fixed Factors, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Two Stage Budgeting, 1971 (Box 7)
    - Additively Separable Utility, 1971 (Box 7)
    - A sketch for The Demand for Related Goods, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Some Engel Curves, 1978-1982 (Box 7)
    - Polynominal Engel Curves, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Polynominal Engel Curves, 1975 (Box 7)
    - Notes on Duality and its Apps. 1977, (2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Generalised Additive Separablity, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Polynominal Engel Curves, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Some Engel Curves, 1978-1982 (Box 8)
    - Facing an Uncertain Future, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Estimating Trends in Leontieff Matrices, (versions 6 and 7) (Box 8)
    - Trends in Leontieff Matrices, 1963 (versions 1 and 2) (Box 8)
    - Aggregates, Activities and Overheads, 1985 (Box 8)
    - 1982 (Box 8)
    - Assembling Efficient Organizations, 1985/6 (Box 8)
    - Notes on Stoker, 1982 (Box 8)
    - More Measures for Fixed Factors, 1987-1989 (Box 8)
    - Equation of Measurement, 1988 (Box 8)
    - Equation of Measurement, 1987 (Box 8)
    - Equation of Measurement, typed (Box 8)
    - Facing an Uncertain Future, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Equation of Measure Degenerate Case (Box 9)
    - Aggregates, Activities and Overheads, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Aggregation in Sht. and Long Run (various) (Box 9)
    - Aggregation in Sht. and Long Run (current), 1989 (Box 9)
    - Equation of Measurement, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
    - Aggregates, Activities, and Overheads, 1982-1984 (Box 9)
    - Comments on James Quirkes Article, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Aggregates, Activities and Overheads, 1980 (Box 9)
    - Elasticity of Demand for Imports (Box 10)
    - Professor Strotz on Specification Error, 1960 (Box 10)
    - Why Disaggregate, 1961 (Box 10)
    - Price Indices, 1962, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Leontieff Matrices, 1963, (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - Aggregation Under Constant Returns, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Estimating Trends in Leontieff Matrices, 1963, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Estimating Trends in Leontieff Matrices (version 5/4) (Box 10)
    - Estimating Trends in Leontieff Matrices (versions 3-5) (Box 10)
    - When are Marginal Frequencies Suff. Stats? 1963 (Box 10)
    - Contingency Tables, 1963 (Box 10)
    - Substitutions in Input/Output Matrices, 1964 (Box 11)
    - Fisher on Identification, 1963 (Box 11)
    - Preference Revealed, 1965? (Box 11)
    - Consumer Budgets and Price Indices, 1970 (Box 11)
    - Notes on Divisia Indices, 1970 (Box 11)
    - Four Seminars - Duality, Sep. Agg. 1970 (Box 11)
    - Price Indices and Decentralisation, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Generalized Additive Separablity, 1970 (Box 11)
    - Savings in the absence of uncertainty, 1956 (Box 11)
    - Early work on Klein, 1950 (Box 11)
    - Optimum Tariffs, 195? (Box 11)
    - Welfare Tariffs, 1951 (Box 11)
    - National Income, 1950? (Box 11)
    - Savings, 1956 (Box 11)
    - Klein Aggregates, 1953 (Box 11)
    - Savings (handwritten rough draft), [195?] (Box 12)
    - Savings (Box 12)
    - Savings (typed draft), [195?] (Box 12)
    - Chipman on Lexicography, 1959? (Box 12)
    - Yet another note on classical and Keynesian Systems, [1956?] (Box 12)
    - 1960 (Box 12)
    - Uncertainty, 1954 (Box 12)
    - Dref, RPref and IND/ER RELNS (Box 12)
    - Demand for Fish, 1959 (Box 12)
    - Separable Utility and Aggregation, 1959 (Box 12)
    - Empirical Implications of Utility Tree, 1958 (Box 12)
    - Tariff and Trade in a Two-Good World, 1959 (Box 12)
    - Calculating Latent Vectors - Hotelling, 1960, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Prof. Friedman and the Theory of Choice, 1960, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Savings (Box 12)
  - Conference Proceedings
    - Copies of papers, notes, and programs from conferences, [1970s]-[1980s] (Box 13)
  - Notes
    - Unsorted (Box 14)
    - Engel Curves - Notes for a Seminar, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Notes on Duality, 1977 (Box 15)
    - Generalised Additive Separability, 1970 (Box 15)
    - Price Indices, Notes for a Seminar, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Duality (Box 15)
    - Quasi-Homothetic Tastes and Technologies, 1976 (Box 15)
    - Monopoly - Costs/Taxation and..., 1977 (Box 15)
    - Lecture Notes, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Functions of Pers. Income Theory, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Degenerative Shares, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Housing, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Aggregation (Box 15)
    - Estimating Trends in Leontieff Matrices, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Uniform Dist'ns, 1980 (Box 15)
    - Price Index Project (NBER), 1980 (Box 15)
    - Functional Equations, 1985 (Box 15)
    - State Department Preferences, 1985 (Box 15)
    - Cost Functions - Separable in Skills, 1987 (Box 15)
    - Special Shares (Box 15)
    - Left, Right, Centre, 1987 (Box 15)
    - Decomposable Inequality Measures, 1983 (Box 15)
    - Anderson- Muellbauer, 1983 (Box 15)
    - Unsorted (Box 16)
    - Unsorted (Box 17)
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted (Box 18)
    - Unsorted (Box 19)
    - Unsorted (Box 20)
    - Maths Letters, A-Z, [1960s] (Box 21)
    - Maths Letters, A-K, [1970s] (Box 21)
    - Maths Letters, L-Z, [1970s] (Box 21)
    - Maths Letters, A-K, [1980s] (Box 21)
    - Maths Letters, L-Z, [1980s] (Box 21)
    - 1979-1984, A-B (Box 21)
    - 1979-1984, C-H (Box 21)
    - 1979-1984, I-M (Box 21)
    - 1979-1984, N-R (Box 21)
    - 1979-1984, S-Z (Box 21)
    - Unlabelled, (1 Folder) (Box 21)
    - 1985-1987, A-B (Box 22)
    - 1985-1987, C-F (Box 22)
    - 1985-1987, G-H (Box 22)
    - 1985-1987, L-Q (Box 22)
    - 1985-1987, R-S (Box 22)
    - Unlabelled, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Unsorted (Box 23)
    - References, A-C [1960s]-[1970s] (Box 24)
    - References, D-M, [1960s]-[1970s] (Box 24)
    - References, N-Z, [1960s]-[1970s] (Box 24)
    - References for Chairs - Essex, Southampton, Bristol (Box 24)
    - References, A-D - with Index [1970s]-[1980s] (Box 25)
    - References, E-H - with Index, [1970s]-[1980s] (Box 25)
    - References, I-R, [1970s]-[1980s] (Box 25)
    - References, S-Z, [1970s]-[1980s] (Box 25)
    - Drafts, Spares, Applications, (25 folders) (Box 26)
  - Research Reports
    - Graduate student and other miscellaneous papers (Box 27)
    - Graduate student and other miscellaneous papers (Box 28)